A Finding Aid to the Andrew Carnduff Ritchie Papers, 1907-1983, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ritcandr2
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition and Project Files, 1949-1978; Series 5; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-9, OV 12
  - Stone Mountain Memorial Project, 1958-1960 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Information Agency Modern Sculpture (1960), 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
  - Westchester Art Society Juried Exhibition (1970), 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Western Round Table on Modern Art (Box 8)
    - Correspondence and Planning, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Transcript of Panel Discussions, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Western Round Table on Modern Art Printed Material, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Sculpture Data Sheets, circa 1955 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Alfred Burr Memorial Plans from Box 7, Folder 31, 1971-1972 (Box OV 12)
  - Oversized Stone Mountain Memorial Scale Drawing from Box 8, Folder 22, circa 1959 (Box OV 12)
- Teaching Files, 1957-1974; Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet Box 9
  This series consists of Ritchie's teaching files, the bulk of which documents the Museum Training Fellowship, a curatorial training program at the Yale University Art Gallery. There are also folders documenting Ritchie's professorship at Williams College and as a visiting scholar and lecturer at the University of Sydney and the University of East Anglia. File contents vary but often contain correspondence, program outlines, course materials, recommendations, and a few student papers.
  - Museum Training Fellowship (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1968 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    - Course Material, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Hunter, Robert, 1964-1967 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Mitchell, William, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Yassin, Robert A., 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - University of East Anglia Scholar in Residence, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - University of East Anglia Staff Housing Floor Plans, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - University of Sydney, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Williams College Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Williams College Course Material, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
  - Recommendations, 1957-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Guggenheim Foundation Recommendations, 1958-1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Student Papers and Notes, 1965-1974 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Printed Material, 1928-1978; Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  The bulk of the printed material consists of news clippings, some of which are arranged by subject, along with articles by Andrew Ritchie, press releases, magazines, bulletins, and a few exhibition catalogs.
  This series is arranged by document type. Some of the news clippings are arranged by subject and others are arranged chronologically.
  - Articles by Andrew Ritchie, 1939-1953 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Albright Art Gallery Clippings, 1942-1951 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Art Institute of Chicago 20th Century Sculpture Exhibition Clippings, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Black Mountain College and Joseph Albers Clippings, 1935-1946 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Dunn International Exhibition Clippings, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Edouard Vuillard Exhibition Clippings, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Mellon Gift to Yale Clippings, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - William Zorach Clippings and Printed Material, circa 1938-1956 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Yale Art Gallery Book Review Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Yale Art Gallery Director Appointment Clippings, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - News Clippings, 1945-1971 (Box 9, Folder 29-30)
  - News Clippings, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Albright Art Gallery Exhibition Catalogs, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1949-circa 1950 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Magazines, 1947-1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Programs and Booklets, 1928-1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Photographs, 1935-1982; Series 8; 0.9 Linear feet Box 10, OV 13
  This series mostly consists of black and white photographs of Andrew Ritchie and his wife with artists, friends, and colleagues at art openings and events. There is one small album of photographs of a birthday party for Jane Ritchie. There are numerous formal portraits of Andrew Ritchie at various points in his career, some of which were taken by the photographer Hans Namuth, and a few portraits of artists. Also included are photographs of artwork. The photographs of events contain images of Ritchie with artists and colleagues. Most of the photographs have annotations written on the verso identifying people, but not much information on the events or locations.
  This series is arranged by subject.
  - Album of Jane Ritchie's Birthday Party, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Jane and Andrew Ritchie Portraits, circa 1935-circa 1950 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Andrew Ritchie Portraits for the Museum of Modern Art, 1949-1957 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Andrew Ritchie Portraits by Hans Namuth, circa 1953 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in OV 13.
  - Andrew Ritchie Portraits with Artwork, 1960-1965 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Andrew Ritchie Portraits for Yale Art Gallery, circa 1960-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Andrew Ritchie Photographs by Russell Lynes, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Assorted Andrew Ritchie Portraits, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Canaan House and Unidentified Houses, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Group Portraits of Artists with Andrew Ritchie, circa 1950-circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Portraits of Artists and Colleagues, circa 1950-1982 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified Artists and Colleagues, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Antwerp Trip, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Artwork from Andrew Ritchie Collection, circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Ciborium at Victoria and Albert Museum, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Ciboria and Medieval Art, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
  - Ciboria and Medieval Art Negatives, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - George Rickey Sculpture Installation at Yale, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Henry Moore Sculpture Installation at Yale, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Artists and Others with Henry Moore Sculpture, circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Includes images of Andrew Ritchie, artists, and donors with the sculpture.
  - Henry Moore Sculptures, 1966-1972 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Mellon Collection Opening, circa 1966 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - William de Kooning Springs Fireplace Studio, circa 1965 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Art Openings and Events, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 31-33)
  - Assorted Personal Photographs, circa 1930-circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    Includes images of relatives, family gatherings, and events.
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Oversized Andrew Ritchie Portraits from Box 10, Folder 9, circa 1953 (Box OV 13)
  - Oversized Photographs of Artists and Colleagues from Box 10, Folder 17, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box OV 13)
  - Oversized Photograph from Box 10, Folder 35, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box OV 13)